By the way...
I told him. I told Taiki that I like him.
[gasps softly]
[wind blowing]
Oh, gotcha.
[grunts hesitantly] Uh, so...
I mean, since the two of you
are living together,
I thought I should give you
a heads-up, right?
But I don't want you to treat me
differently or anything.
Actually, for the time being,
I'm not staying with Taiki and his family.
Uh?
My grandfather has to have surgery.
That's why my mom's back
in Japan for a while.
I'm gonna stay with her until
my grandfather's procedure in a month.
[exclaims in surprise]
Oh, I didn't know!
I hope his surgery goes smoothly
and there aren't any issues.
I'll go and take care
of some other things now,
so please take your time
with the copy machine!
See you.
[door sliding]
[machine whirring]
[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
EPISODE 17
OF COURSE I WANT TO SEE IT
[both] Thank you for the practice match.
[boy] Taiki!
You've stepped it up recently.
You look more relaxed on the court,
and your movement's less rigid.
Thanks for saying that.
I don't know.
I don't feel like any of that's true.
I can score more points than I used to,
and my movement on the court is better.
So then...
why am I feeling so...
stuck.
[Coach Yuasa] Gather 'round!
Scheduling one's been tricky, but we now
have a practice match on Saturday.
Who are we up against?
[Coach Yuasa] Hold on, hold on.
We'll be playing Sajikawa High School.
SAJIKAWA
[gasps softly]
[♪ mellow music playing]
- [Taiki] A rematch?
- [boy 1] Really? Heck yeah!
[boy 2] We won't get to play
against Hyodo though.
Even without the third-years,
that team has a lotta talent.
For next year's nationals,
Sajikawa is our biggest obstacle
to overcome.
[all] Yes, sir!
This is great timing.
I was hoping to go up
against that first-year.
- [boy] Who, Yusa?
- Yeah, the one whose face says,
"I wear turtlenecks in the winter." Uh...
[boy] What kind of a face is that?
Okay, what's up with this nervous act.
You've lost to the guy already,
just give it your best shot.
[boy] Not much of a pep talk, Haryu.
[Taiki] I'll do my best.
[Hina] So, word on the street is...
SNOW WHITE
...you have a practice match on Saturday.
[Taiki] You can run, read your script,
or talk, but pick one.
But it's more efficient this way.
They say that exercise
helps you memorize things better.
You can do it all, can't you?
I don't have gymnastics Saturday,
but I'm gonna be here for rehearsal,
so I can come cheer you on
while you're playing.
- It's okay.
- Huh?
[Taiki] It's only a practice match.
[Hina] But you're facing
a rival school, right?
[Taiki] Yeah, we are, but...
Wasn't the match
you lost before to this team?
[Taiki] Oh, right,
Hina was there that day.
[Hina] Going up against a team like that...
don't you need your fan club?
My fan club, huh?
And anyway, it'd be nice
to see the guy I like doing his best.
Why'd you bring that up outta... Uh...
You can't just turn around like that
all of a sudden!
Someone's gonna get hurt
if you don't look where you're going!
- Jeez! You big, dumb, stupid...
- Ow!
- Okay, okay, I got it! Hey! Come on!
- [Hina whines]
[panting]
EIMEI PRIVATE HIGH SCHOOL
- Good morning.
[racket swooshing]
[grunts]
[pants]
- [door opens]
- [exclaims softly]
Oh, well, good morning.
Morning.
Wow, you're fired up today.
I guess... kinda.
You're getting ready
for the practice match?
[Taiki] Hm?
This gym is a rumor mill.
Word really gets around.
Saturday, right?
My practice ends at noon,
so I'll come see you after.
- [Taiki] Huh?
- Hm?
I mean, this isn't really the kind
of thing you need to come watch.
But I think it's gonna be fun.
It's not like it's an official match
or anything, so...
It isn't really something
that's worth seeing.
No way. Of course I wanna see it.
[♪ peaceful music playing]
[Hina] It'd be nice to see
the guy I like doing his best.
[Taiki grunts softly]
[Chinatsu] Hm?
Oh, no, it's nothing.
[Taiki] It's only 'cause
Hina put that in my head.
Well, I guess I have no right to stop you.
Uh-huh. So, I'll be there.
I can't miss your epic gameplay,
Morning Practice Pal. [chuckles]
[gasps softly]
[racket whipping]
Taiki! What have you been eating?
You got even better, again!
[Taiki] I haven't eaten
anything different.
I still have so much I need to work on.
He was one step ahead of me.
That's exactly how it felt.
[boy] Yo, did you hear?
Yusa from Sajikawa beat one of the players
from the Japan Rusters.
Wait, he beat a player at pro-level?
He's still a first-year, right?
[boy] He's a real beast.
Tanigawa! Let's play another match!
Again?
[Nishida] Taiki...
Consider playing against me, your captain.
Oh, no, don't try and get outta this.
- Loser has to plank for five minutes.
- [Nishida] Oh!
But don't you think someone
should knock him down a peg or two
since he's on a winning streak?
I'm not sweatin' it.
He doesn't seem pleased even when he wins.
Even when people see you doing well,
sometimes it's impossible
to accept that validation.
[Nishida grunts]
The thing is, he's been
practicing so hard, and getting better.
I think he's pushing himself pretty hard
'cause he wants to beat that Sajikawa kid.
It's got to be tough
putting in all this hard work
and feeling like you're not improving.
Okay, sensei, then go
give him some advice.
[Haryu] No, thanks.
I'm competing for one of the spots
at nationals next year, too.
I need my underclassmen
to struggle just a little bit.
You're so immature. This calls for...
- the captain to step--
- [Coach Yuasa] Nishida!
[exclaims] Yes!
Did you sign the club's
expenses application?
Oh, I'm sorry about that, sir!
I was planning to do it later,
but I got busy with stuff for
the Cultural Festival. I'm really sorry!
[bell chiming]
[♪ happy music playing]
This apple is so glossy. It looks great!
We got it at the hundred-yen shop,
and then Hina gave it a coat of paint.
[girl 2] Something about it
"lacking luster."
Actually, where is she?
[girl 1] I think she's in the classroom
rehearsing lines.
Oh, I see.
Hina. Can I help you with anything?
[♪ grandiose music playing]
- She's dead!
- Nuh-uh.
I was just practicing for the play!
Oh, yeah, the last scene
where Snow White wakes up.
It's the only scene where I don't know
how I'm supposed to look.
I can help you rehearse.
Huh?
Wouldn't it be easier
with a scene partner?
[Hina] It would be, but...
SNOW WHITE SCRIPT
THE PRINCE KISSES HER
- Not doing that!
- Yeah, obviously!
[Hina sighs]
[clears throat]
All righty, so what are you
having trouble with?
How are you supposed to look
when you're coming back
from the brink of death?
That's trouble all right.
And then, as if that wasn't enough,
the queen tricked her
into eating a poison apple.
If we look at it from the perspective
that Snow White knows that...
[cackling]
I am the fairest of them all!
I'll never forgive you!
I shall have your head for this!
Now bring me my sword!
You're too bloodthirsty.
I know! The prince is there when
she wakes up, so her heart skips a beat.
[Hina] Who the hell are you?
[Taiki] Now you're too suspicious.
I know that.
This is not the way to play it.
What do I do? This scene really matters.
And I have to perform well at the end.
A near death experience...
is sorta like
surviving finals week, right?
- You're amazing, you know that, Hina?
- Huh?
You could be doing this
without thinking so hard,
but instead, you're giving it your all.
You've always got the script,
reading it over and over.
If it were me,
I'd just look happy in this scene.
When I take something on,
I really go for it.
- Aren't you the same way?
- Huh?
One second, you're in our classroom
helping with the play,
then the next, you're back
in the gym for badminton practice.
[laughs]
You're also really amazing, Taiki.
[grunts softly]
[Hina] You know, everyone was saying that!
Anyway, let's get to rehearsing!
Maybe we should just run the scene
and see how it goes.
Then I'll start
from the line before yours.
I've been feeling overwhelmed lately,
so I'm glad to hear
I've been doing my job well.
"Oh, Snow White,
I beg you, please wake up."
There.
You have been kissed.
Hina?
Is this part of your acting?
I can't.
I couldn't help
but imagine the real thing.
Kissing you for real, Taiki.
What?
[heartbeat thumping]
Wanna do it for real?
[heartbeat thumping continues]
[Taiki gasps]
[Hina] Wanna do it for real?
No, I don't.
[Hina] Well, I know that!
If you'd said yes,
that would've been a turnoff!
Although...
your heart skipped a beat, didn't it?
This is all part
of the great Hina's strategy!
Well,
I guess I'll go see
how everyone else is doing.
[Taiki sighs]
[groans]
[Hina] I like you.
A romantic way.
That's fine, as long as it reminds you
that I have a crush on you, Taiki.
[bangs on table]
[groans]
[exhales]
[rackets swooshing]
[sneakers screeching]
- [grunts]
- [boy] Game, set, match.
[Taiki pants]
[Taiki] Why?
I can beat other people,
and yet the gap between our scores
has only gotten wider.
I can't believe
how much work I have to do.
And at the very least,
Yusa was better than this.
Hey, Taiki.
Shots without confidence behind them...
don't work on me.
Duh.
What?
[Taiki] As if I lack confidence.
[girls squealing excitedly]
Miss Chono, superb as ever!
- I don't, but...
- [Nagisa] Natsu!
Nice!
[Taiki] I'm just pathetic.
[Nishida] What?
Guys, Class D is having a curry tasting!
[stomach rumbling]
Let's go get some!
Man, I hate curry.
Does such a person exist?
Curry, curry!
I'll eat the curry! I'll drink the curry!
[Haryu] Hey, Chii.
Oh, hey, Haryu.
You got night practice?
Not tonight,
but I had to stay
for the Cultural Festival stuff.
Wow I'm impressed.
Since you're busy with practice, too.
You really are self-disciplined, huh?
No way, I'm not at all.
You're the first person
at practice every day,
that means in my book,
you are self-disciplined.
[chuckles]
Well Inomata, from your team,
sometimes beats me to practice,
now that you mention it.
I would say Taiki's more diligent
than self-disciplined.
I hear that they have frankfurters, too!
For real? Let's franken go!
What's the difference?
You're a sadist, and he's a masochist.
You know when you wanna beat someone,
and that's the goal that you set,
you get focused
on all the things you can't do,
and stop feeling good
about the things you can do.
But that's like wandering
through the desert without water.
Why would you even do it?
Taiki is so focused on his shortcomings,
that he forgets
to drink some water, you know?
I get that.
Him wanting so badly
just to hurry up and move forward.
There are some people who drink
plenty of water, and they still give up.
But...
if you don't want to give up,
you just have to keep moving your legs.
Because stopping
is what really torments you.
I'd say you got a point.
All righty then.
I'm headed to night practice.
Haryu.
If you are that worried about him,
offering him some water
might not be a bad thing.
Besides, you are
an upperclassman after all.
You know, I could use some water myself.
[coins jingling]
- [beeps]
- [clattering]
Hey, uh, Taiki...
Yes?
[grunts]
You're eating curry right now?
It's from Captain Nishida.
[Haryu] Him, of all people...
He's a nice captain, isn't he?
I was planning on practicing with you,
guess I'll ask Kyo.
[Taiki] Wait, hold on!
Oh. Could I have that water?
The curry was spicy.
- [Haryu] As if!
- [Taiki] Why not, though! Come on!
[boy 1] Where are the birdies?
[boy 2] Got 'em right here.
[Nishida] Someone go get coach!
I'll go and find him!
[Taiki] This current version of me...
is pathetic.
Hina confessed her feelings to me,
and said she didn't need an answer back,
but now I have no idea
how to move forward.
And as an athlete...
I'm the only one...
[♪ emotional music playing]
not making any progress.
That's why...
[guy] Excuse me.
[gasps softly]
Could you point me to where the gym is?
[Taiki] At least.
[closing theme song playing]